[
 {
  "Question": "ప్రస్తుతం జరుగుతున్న బోధనాభ్యసన ప్రక్రియలతో సంబంధం లేని మూల్యాంకనం",
  "A": "సంగ్రహణాత్మక మదింపు",
  "B": "నిర్మాణాత్మక మదింపు",
  "C": "యూనిట్ టెస్ట్",
  "D": "డైలీ టెస్ట్",
  "Answer": "సంగ్రహణాత్మక మదింపు"
 },
 {
  "Question": "కర్రిక్యులమ్ (Curriculum) అనే పదం ఏ భాషకు సంబంధించినది.",
  "A": "లాటిన్",
  "B": "ఫ్రెంచ్",
  "C": "ఇంగ్లీష్",
  "D": "సంస్కృతం",
  "Answer": "లాటిన్"
 },
 {
  "Question": "విద్యార్థి క్షేత్రస్థాయిలో సమాచారాన్ని సేకరించడం, పట్టికలలో నమోదు చేయడం, సమాచారాన్ని విశ్లేషించడం, అభిప్రాయాలను వ్యక్తపరచడం వంటివి ఈ క్రింది వానిలో దేనికి సంబంధించినది",
  "A": "పరిపుష్టి",
  "B": "ప్రాజెక్ట్ పని",
  "C": "సలహాలు",
  "D": "అభిప్రాయాలు",
  "Answer": "ప్రాజెక్ట్ పని"
 },
 {
  "Question": "సారూప్యత గల భావనలు లేదా అంశాలను అభ్యసన ప్రక్రియలో ఇమిడ్చి నట్లయితే అభ్యసన సులువుగా జరుగుతుంది. ఇది క్రింది నియమమును సూచించును",
  "A": " సారూప్య నియమం",
  "B": "అంతరృష్టి అభ్యసనం",
  "C": "సంసర్గ నియమం",
  "D": "అవిచ్ఛిన్నత నియమం",
  "Answer": " సారూప్య నియమం"
 },
 {
  "Question": "గణితానికి సంబంధించిన అంశాలైన సంఖ్యలు, సంఖ్యా ప్రక్రియలు, కొలతలు, దశాంశాలు, శాతాలు మొదలగు సామర్థ్యాలను పెంపొందించడానికి మాత్రమే పరిమితమైతే అది ఏ రకానికి చెందిన విలువను తెలుపును.           ",
  "A": "సాంఘిక విలువ",
  "B": "సంకుచిత విలువ",
  "C": "ఉన్నత విలువ",
  "D": "వృత్తిపరమైన విలువ",
  "Answer": "సంకుచిత విలువ"
 },       
 {
  "Question": "గణితంలోని వివిధ శాఖల మధ్య లేదా ఒకే శాఖలోని వివిధ అంశాల మధ్యగల సంబంధం",
  "A": "మదింపు",
  "B": "బాహ్య సహసంబంధం",
  "C": " అంతర్గత సహసంబంధం",
  "D": "ఖచ్చితత్వం",
  "Answer": " అంతర్గత సహసంబంధం"
 },
 {
  "Question": "28 సెం.మీ. వ్యాసము గల వృత్తము యొక్క వైశాల్యము (చ. సెం.మీ. లలో)",
  "A": " 616",
  "B": "1000",
  "C": "900",
  "D": "500",
  "Answer": "500"
 },
 {
  "Question": "ఘనపరిమాణం 625 సెం.మీ. మరియు భూ. వైశాల్యం 25 సెం.మీ.” కలిగిన దీర్ఘఘనం ఎత్తు (సెం.మీ. లలో)",
  "A": "25",
  "B": "625",
  "C": " 35",
  "D": " 11",
  "Answer": "25"
 },
 {
  "Question": "లీపు సంవత్సరం కానిది",
  "A": "1988",
  "B": "1994",
  "C": "1992",
  "D": "1996",
  "Answer": "1994"
 },
 {
  "Question": "100 లీటర్లను మిల్లీ లీటర్లలోకి మార్చిన",
  "A": "10000 మిల్లీ లీటర్ల",
  "B": "1000 మిల్లీ లీటర్ల",
  "C": "100 మిల్లీ లీటర్ల",
  "D": "100000 మిల్లీ లీటర్ల",
  "Answer": "100000 మిల్లీ లీటర్ల"
 },
 {
  "Question": " 2x²+x-a=5 , x=0 అయితే 'a' విలువ ",
  "A": "5",
  "B": "-5",
  "C": "-7",
  "D": "6",
  "Answer": "-5"
 },
 {
  "Question": "3x10 సాధారణ రూపంలో తెలపండి.",
  "A": "0.0005",
  "B": "0.0003",
  "C": "0.00005",
  "D": "0.00003",
  "Answer": "0.00003"
 },
 {
  "Question": "కింది కోణాలలో పూరక కోణాల జత",
  "A": "65 degrees, 55 degres",
  "B": "35 degrees, 75 degres",
  "C": "45 degrees, 55 degres",
  "D": "35 degrees, 60 degres",
  "Answer": "35 degrees, 55 degres"
 },
 {
  "Question": "క్రింది వాటిలో 3D (త్రిమితీయ) ఆకారం కానిది",
  "A": " కోన్ ఐస్క్రీం",
  "B": "కాగితం",
  "C": "పాచిక",
  "D": "చెక్క",
  "Answer": "కాగితం"
 },
 {
  "Question": "భుజాల సంఖ్య గల బహుభుజి యొక్క పేరు",
  "A": "త్రిభుజం",
  "B": "షడ్భుజి",
  "C": "పంచభుజి",
  "D": "చతుర్భుజం",
  "Answer": "పంచభుజి"
 },
 {
  "Question": "2 పొడవులు + 2 వెడల్పులు =",
  "A": " త్రిభుజం చుట్టుకొలత",
  "B": "దీర్ఘచతురస్ర వైశాల్యం",
  "C": "చతురస్రం వైశాల్యం",
  "D": " దీర్ఘచతురస్ర చుట్టుకొలత",
  "Answer": " దీర్ఘచతురస్ర చుట్టుకొలత"
 },
 {
  "Question": "విద్యార్థుల బృందం సైన్స్ పరీక్షలో సాధించిన మార్కులు (100కి) 75, 81, 95, 56, 48, 39, 85, 90, 76 2 85.

పొందిన సగటు మార్కులు",
  "A": "73",
  "B": " 72",
  "C": "74",
  "D": "75",
  "Answer": "73"
 },
 {
  "Question": "ఒక నగర జనాభా 25,000 నుండి 24,500కు తగ్గింది. అయిన తగ్గుదల శాతం",
  "A": "1%",
  "B": "2%",
  "C": "3%",
  "D": "4%",
  "Answer": "2%"
 },
 {
  "Question": "ఒక దుకాణంలో ఒక గౌను ఖరీదు ₹750. దానిపై 10% అమ్మకపు పన్ను విధించిన చెల్లించవలసిన బిల్లు",
  "A": "775",
  "B": "800",
  "C": "825",
  "D": "850",
  "Answer": "825"
 },
 {
  "Question": "87 ని శాతంగా మార్చిన",
  "A": "870%",
  "B": "77%",
  "C": "97%",
  "D": "87%",
  "Answer": "87%"
 },
 {
  "Question": "ఒక పశువుల పాకలో 200 గేదెలు మరియ 250 ఆవులు ఉన్నాయి. అయితే గేదెలు మరియు ఆవుల నిష్పత్తి",
  "A": " 4:5",
  "B": " 5:4",
  "C": "1:4",
  "D": "3:4",
  "Answer": " 4:5"
 },
 {
  "Question": "110592 యొక్క ఘన మూలం",
  "A": "76",
  "B": "48",
  "C": "58",
  "D": "28",
  "Answer": "48"
 },
 {
  "Question": "ఒక రెండంకెల సంఖ్యలోని ఒక అంకె మరో అంకెకు మూడు రెట్లు. ఈ రెండంకెల సంఖ్యలోని అంకెలను తారుమారు చేయగా వచ్చే సంఖ్యను, ఆ సంఖ్యకు కలిపితే 88 వస్తుంది. అయితే ఆ సంఖ్య",
  "A": "42",
  "B": "56",
  "C": "72",
  "D": "26",
  "Answer": "26"
 },
 {
  "Question": "He",
  "A": "a",
  "B": "an",
  "C": "the",
  "D": "none",
  "Answer": "an"
 },
 {
  "Question": "ఒక బిలియన్ విలువ",
  "A": "10 మిలియన్లు",
  "B": " 100 మిలియన్లు",
  "C": "1000 మిలియన్లు",
  "D": " 10000 మిలియన్లు",
  "Answer": "1000 మిలియన్లు"
 },
 {
  "Question": "ప్రధానమంత్రి సహాయనిధికి పంపడానికి ఒక్కొక్క విద్యార్థి ₹110 చొప్పున 5 గురు విద్యార్థులు డబ్బు పోగుచేశారు. వారు సేకరించిన మొత్తం సొమ్ము",
  "A": "550",
  "B": "650",
  "C": "555",
  "D": "660",
  "Answer": "550"
 },
 {
  "Question": "90. Choose the correct statement regarding the definite article 'the'",
  "A": "The' is used before a singular noun that indicates somebody's profession",
  "B": " 'The' is used to introduce nouns for the first time",
  "C": "'The' is used to refer to specific nouns already known to the listener.",
  "D": " 'The' is not used before nouns.",
  "Answer": "'The' is used to refer to specific nouns already known to the listener."
 },
 {
  "Question": " Choose the sentence in which 'may' is expressing possibility.",
  "A": "It may snow tomorrow.",
  "B": " May I borrow your pen?",
  "C": "You may leave the room.",
  "D": " You may leave the room.",
  "Answer": "It may snow tomorrow."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Select the sentence that contains a subordinating clause.",
  "A": "I will go to the beach along with him.",
  "B": "After we finish dinner, we can go for a walk.",
  "C": "The dog barked loudly all night.",
  "D": " She danced gracefully across the stage.",
  "Answer": "After we finish dinner, we can go for a walk."
 },
 {
  "Question": "The tiger strategically attacks

Choose the option that fits the blank.",
  "A": " as against off",
  "B": "from under in",
  "C": "from behind",
  "D": "as against off",
  "Answer": "from behind"
 },
 {
  "Question": " Sentence structures can be practised by",
  "A": "one word answers",
  "B": "multiple choice questions",
  "C": "substitution tables",
  "D": "essay type questions",
  "Answer": "substitution tables"
 },
 {
  "Question": "One of the following makes the class lively and learners practice language element lively and interestingly.",
  "A": "Use of audio-visual aids",
  "B": "Paper - pencil test",
  "C": "Use of a calculator",
  "D": "Correct pronunciation",
  "Answer": "Use of audio-visual aids"
 },
 {
  "Question": " Read the following passage.
The city streets bustled with life, as cars honked their horns and pedestrians hurried along the sidewalks.
  Neon signs illuminated the night sky, casting a colorful glow on the throngs of people below. 
  Amidst the hustle and bustle, street performers entertained crowds with music and acrobatics, 
  adding to the vibrant energy of the urban landscape.
Choose the correct statement based on the passage:",
  "A": "The city streets were dimly lit by traditional gas lamps.",
  "B": "Street performers captivated audiences with their silent performances",
  "C": "Pedestrians were walking leisurely along the streets.",
  "D": "The urban landscape was full of life or activity.",
  "Answer": "The urban landscape was full of life or activity."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Read the following passage.
The city streets bustled with life, as cars honked their horns and pedestrians hurried along the sidewalks.
  Neon signs illuminated the night sky, casting a colorful glow on the throngs of people below. Amidst the hustle and bustle,
  street performers entertained crowds with music and acrobatics, adding to the vibrant energy of the urban landscape.
Select the correct statement based on the passage:",
  "A": "The city streets were deserted and quiet.",
  "B": "Street performers added pleasure to the urban scene.",
  "C": " Neon signs were turned off, leaving the streets in darkness.",
  "D": " Cars moved smoothly along the streets without any honking.",
  "Answer": "Street performers added pleasure to the urban scene."
 },
 {
  "Question": "A textbook should the teacher's instruction.
Choose the option that fits the blank.",
  "A": "overcome",
  "B": "speculate",
  "C": "dominate",
  "D": "supplement",
  "Answer": "supplement"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Planning the blackboard work in a systematic way comes under",
  "A": " post teaching stage",
  "B": "while teaching stage",
  "C": "pre teaching stage",
  "D": " evaluation",
  "Answer": "pre teaching stage"
 },
 {
  "Question": "The vocabulary we use to communicate through spoken form or written form is:",
  "A": "receptive vocabulary",
  "B": "active vocabulary",
  "C": "dead vocabulary",
  "D": "passive vocabulary",
  "Answer": "active vocabulary"
 },
 {
  "Question": "The following is not a technique of reading.",
  "A": "Extrapolating",
  "B": "Intensive reading",
  "C": "Scanning",
  "D": "Skimming",
  "Answer": "Extrapolating"
 },
 {
  "Question": "He lived alone, was not a mixer, had few friends and didn't like spending time in idle chat.
Choose the antonym of the word 'like'",
  "A": "love",
  "B": "an",
  "C": "enjoy",
  "D": "hate",
  "Answer": "dislike"
 },
 {
  "Question": "We are aware, always, of the pain and horrors of war."

Choose the synonym of the word 'aware'",
  "A": "unconscious",
  "B": "informed",
  "C": "ignorant",
  "D": "uninformed",
  "Answer": "informed"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Choose the correctly spelt word.",
  "A": "Comonelitee",
  "B": "Commonelity",
  "C": "Commonality",
  "D": "Comonality",
  "Answer": "Commonality"
 },
 {
  "Question": "An expression used to convey praise.
Choose one word substitute for the expression above.",
  "A": "cliché",
  "B": "euphoria",
  "C": "rebuke",
  "D": "compliment",
  "Answer": "compliment"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Diabetes much fast food. very common among people who consume too
   Choose the correct verb that fits the blank.",
  "A": "have",
  "B": " were",
  "C": "are",
  "D": "is",
  "Answer": "is"
 },
 {
  "Question": "He said to me, "How long will you stay here?"
Choose the indirect speech for the sentence above.",
  "A": "He told me how long he would stay there.",
  "B": "He asked me how long would I stay here.",
  "C": "He asked me how long I would stay here.",
  "D": "He asked me how long I would stay there.",
  "Answer": "He asked me how long I would stay there."
 },
 {
  "Question": " Choose the sentence type that gives instructions or requests.",
  "A": "Declarative sentence",
  "B": "Exclamatory sentence",
  "C": "Imperative sentence",
  "D": "Interrogative sentence",
  "Answer": "Imperative sentence"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Choose the phrasal verb that means 'to quit or surrender, often after a struggle or effort'.",
  "A": "give up",
  "B": " run out",
  "C": "get over",
  "D": "take up",
  "Answer": "give up"
 },
 {
  "Question": "Select the compound sentence from the following",
  "A": "He enjoys reading books and she likes watching movies.",
  "B": "The students studied hard because they had an exam.",
  "C": "She cooked the dinner while she set the table.",
  "D": " After the game, we went out for pizza.",
  "Answer": "He enjoys reading books and she likes watching movies."
 },
 {
  "Question": "Select the superlative form of the adverb 'quickly'",
  "A": "quickerly",
  "B": " most quickly",
  "C": "quicker",
  "D": "quick",
  "Answer": " most quickly"
 },
 {
  "Question": " "We enjoyed ourselves at the party." Identify the type of pronoun of the underlined word in the sentence above.",
  "A": "Personal pronoun",
  "B": "Possessive pronoun",
  "C": "Demonstrative pronoun",
  "D": "Reflexive pronoun",
  "Answer": "Reflexive pronoun"
 }
]
